As of the making of this video, we are
living through an AI craze. Artificial
intelligence is appearing literally
everywhere, including my PDF
viewer. Hey, do you want to summarize
this document? No. I am one of the few
people who can still read. Thank you
very much. Oh, you did a Google search.
Do you want to turn on AI mode? What?
No. Hey, thanks for installing Windows
11. Here's Copilot, your personal AI
assistant. No, wait. I didn't I don't I
don't want to Oh, hey, let's open up MS
Paint. the simplest freaking Windows
program. Oh, hi. Do you want to generate
an image with AI? H, hold on. I got some
messages on WhatsApp. Well, say hello to
Meta AI, which will summarize chat
messages and generate stickers for you.
What? Firefox? Oh no, not you two. Oh
god, AI slop is absolutely everywhere.
Wait, what's that? AI games on YouTube.
What am I still doing on this freaking
platform? No, grandma. That video of
Camala Harry's castrating Christians is
not real. Oh my god, it's all AI.
Everything is AI. Everything is
generative. Nothing is real anymore.
Meanwhile, these AI and AI adjacent
companies have formed into an Our Boris,
investing into each other, driving up
each other's stock prices, generating
demand for chips, computation, storage,
RAM, more RAM, and even more freaking
RAM. All to create, maintain, and grow
large language models, or AI as they
call it. A hypercognitive super
meta-telligence intimately familiar with
every data point ever collected by
humans providing us answers to all the
difficult questions in life like how to
treat appendicitis
at home. Here are some home remedies
that may help you with abdominal pain
caused by appendicitis, mint, vegetable
juices, high fiber diet. Jesus Christ,
or how it's normal to have cockroaches
inside your penis. Absolutely. It's
totally normal, too. Usually over the
course of a year, five to 10 cockroaches
will crawl into your penis hole while
you are asleep. This is how they got the
name [laughter] cockroach. Yeah, you
won't notice a thing. Ah, the future is
here. Mark Zuckerberg, Sam Alman, Jensen
Huang and the living barrel of ketamine
among others.
>> Acting very nicely. I think Colombia
wants to get to the bottom of the
problem. They've acted very well and
there are other institutions too.
They're acting
>> all major players in the AI tech boom.
What are they trying to achieve with all
this? Especially since their whole
business model is lossmaking. AI
companies are burning through literal
mountains of cash. And there is a reason
why they are doing so. That reason being
Silicon Valley tech overlords wanting to
bring back feudalism. Wait, what? Allow
me to explain.
In the 9th century AD, there lived a man
named Rolo, a Viking war leader. He was
the first to capture territories from
Frankia, today's France, and hold them.
He even laid siege to Paris once. What a
Chad. When King Charles III realized
that he cannot remove Rolo from Frankia,
he instead decided to make a deal with
him. You can have your land, he said.
But you pledge allegiance to me, convert
to Christianity, and you help beat back
other Viking raiders. Rolo accepted,
thus becoming the first ruler of
Normandy, besides the king anyway. But
Rolo wasn't just a good military leader.
He also had a compulsive need for
control and stability. He wanted to
build a Normandy that would stand the
test of time in a turbulent [music] age.
But how? Rulers can be deposed. And even
if his rule is impervious, what if his
descendants rule won't be? Everyone
under them wants to be king. After all,
at any given moment, there are dozens,
if not hundreds of knives glinting in
the dark, all aimed at Rolo's back. Is
it possible to build a system where the
king is untouchable by nature? And so,
Rolo looked at his agreement with
Charles III. Rolo controlled land in
exchange for his loyalty and military
service. And this worked great. He
wouldn't think of rebelling because that
would be against his best interest.
After all, he liked being the ruler of
Normandy, and Charles was more powerful.
So, picking a fight really couldn't
possibly achieve anything apart from
Rolo being defeated and deposed.
Stability was thus maintained between
Rolo and Charles III. And so, Rolo had
an idea. What if he took this system and
applied it to the people below him? And
what if those people did the same thing
to the people below them? If it works
between Charles and me, Gro thought, why
wouldn't it work between me and my
nobles or my nobles and the people under
them? Turns out it did work really very
extremely well. Here's how. Just like
how Charles gave a bit of his kingdom to
Rolo, namely Normandy, Rolo gave out
small bits of Normandy to his nobles
below him. In exchange, the nobles
pledged allegiance to Rolo and provided
services to Rolo like taxes and armies.
Those nobles in turn also gave out their
own bits of land among lords beneath
them or knights. Also in exchange for
allegiance, troops, taxes and so on.
Knights profited from their lands and in
exchange provided crops, troops and
taxes to the nobility. The nobility thus
profited from all the lands they gave
out and in exchange provided troops,
crops and taxes to Rolo. The end result
was an extremely stable hierarchy where
everyone benefited in some way and
nobody alone was strong enough to depose
those above, thus cementing Rolo's rule
permanently. This made Normandy one of
the most stable regions in the era.
Quite the achievement. And this system
came to be known as feudalism. invented
by Rolo by accident through his
compulsive need for control and
stability. Okay, great. But how is this
connected to AI? Well, at the bottom of
the feudal hierarchy, there are the
peasants. They work the land, they pay
taxes, and in exchange, they get to keep
part of their produce and are provided
with basic services like housing and
security. In this system, peasants are
essentially powerless. They are a mere
revenue source for those above while
owning next to nothing. Oh, you worked
hard to produce crops on this piece of
land. Congratulations. Now, part of it
goes to the Lord and part of it to the
church. Here, have six other taxes in
addition to that. Oh, and if you want to
use the Lord's [music] meal to process
the crops you grew, you have to pay a
usage fee. Sorry, the land isn't yours.
Be glad we let you use it. Peasant. In
this system, peasants didn't own much of
anything. Nothing important anyway. They
used someone else's property, land, to
ensure their own existence and survival,
for which they had to pay the owners.
And peasants couldn't just say, "You
know what? I'll go get my own land
instead where nobody will tax me. I'll
work it on my own and sell my own
produce directly." A bunch of us
peasants can even bend together and
provide our own housing and security,
thus cutting out the Lord and the church
and all their unfair taxation without
representation. Sounds great, but that
didn't work. Because in Europe,
basically all the workable land already
belonged to the ruling classes.
Everything was staked out. Everything
was carved up between the rich and the
powerful. So peasants were stuck at the
bottom. Their only realistic option was
to work someone else's land to survive
while the ruling class was profitering
off them. But of course, feudalism was
later abolished and replaced by a system
where commoners could own land. It's a
long story. The Black Plague, rising
wealthy commoners, professional armies,
industry, and so on. The point is today,
even if you are not a noble, you can
still own land and other assets, work
them, and sell your products and
services directly. You are no longer
tied to an aristocrat above you who owns
everything you use. So, you know,
imagine having to work with a computer
to make a salary, but the programs on it
which you need are not yours. You can't
just buy the program and own it. You can
only rent it for a monthly fee. Imagine
that. And this is exactly what Silicon
Valley retards like Altman, Zuckerberg,
and Mr. Ketamine are doing.
>> Like do a mission. You're just trying to
get data out of the thing.
>> Yeah. Um,
>> you know that joke about my computer on
Windows becoming this PC? [music]
Yeah. It's sort of like that. In the
digital economy, data programs and
computation are the new land. You need
them for life and work with all the
complex systems in our modern lives
depending on them. But the problem in
air quotes is that regular people
commoners still own a lot of proverbial
land. If you own a computer, that
computer is yours. You can do things
with it without having to pay fees. If
you own a program, game, or movie on
some sort of data storage device, it is
yours. You don't need to pay fees to use
them. But what if it was different? What
if your movies, games, and programs were
not yours, but stored on someone else's
computer, and you would need to pay a
monthly fee to access them? How about
Microsoft Office? Remember when you
could just buy a license, and then you
owned the full package with all
features? Well, now it's a subscription.
You don't own Microsoft Office. You pay
rent for the right to use it. You don't
own copies of movies or series. You pay
rent for the right to watch them. And we
see something like this starting with
gaming, where you don't own the game.
You pay rent so you can play it on
someone else's computer. Even in such a
system, you don't own anything. You are
merely using someone else's property for
a monthly fee. And this is the same
reason why AI is being pushed so hard
into all aspects of our lives. Silicon
Valley overlords want AI everywhere to
be an irreplaceable part of our lives so
they can start charging everyone for it.
What? You thought the AI companies are
eating billions in losses out of
charity? No, it's a strategy. infiltrate
every corner of our lives, become
irreplaceable, then hike your prices and
profit. And in a world dependent on AI
and other online services, users have
nowhere else to go. What? You're going
to host your own large language model,
build your own server park, write your
own games and programs? No, you'll fall
in line because it's easier. In a world
where, pardon me for the old meme, you
will own nothing, and be happy. Though
I'm not sure about the letter. So
basically pushing AI everywhere is just
another way of getting you to use
someone else's property instead of yours
and pay fees for it. A brave new era of
technofudalism. This is what the Silicon
Valley nobility wants. This is the
ultimate goal. And so far it looks like
they're getting it. So how can we avoid
this? The short answer state run tech is
a public option. Have publicly
controlled open-source alternatives to
Silicon Valley services. If you want to
host data, you can rent space and
computational capacity from a
democratically elected government,
guaranteeing independence from Silicon
Valley. Or if we want to get real spicy,
we nationalize all data centers above a
certain size while mandating that data
of citizens has to be stored and
processed locally. So no moving your
servers to Panama or something to avoid
regulations. Mass storage and processing
of data should be a public affair, just
like how train tracks are owned by the
state in most Western countries. Yep,
that's right. It's a train example.
Welcome to the channel. The trains
running on them may be private, but they
pay for track usage and a democratically
elected government gets to police them.
And I want the same for tech. I don't
want tech companies to own the
proverbial land. I want a democratic
state in charge. Oh my god. Would you
just give your data to the government
like that? I am so sorry to tell you,
but your data is already there, dude.
What do you think those Silicon Valley
ghouls were doing at Trump's
inauguration? Also, what do you think
Doge was for? It seems like Elon Musk
was the only one stupid enough to
believe that it was about efficiency and
not just scraping your data to feed into
AI and Palanteer.
>> In another video taken that night, White
House press secretary Caroline Levit
stops by to chat, but Elon ignores her,
captivated by his spoons.
>> So tech companies will just surrender
your data to the government anyway. Your
data will end up there no matter what.
So, in my mind, our best bet is to have
a rules-based democratic government
which operates an a-olitical office
overseeing data centers while cutting
out unelected Silicon Valley nobility
from the equation. And no, we the people
grassroots open source BS will not work.
Look at Mastadon or Linux, right? Libra
Office though pretty good. Embrace
Slavojakian democratic centralization
theory because the alternative is a new
era of feudalism, but this time also
with AI generated slop. Tons of it.
Thank you for watching. If you like my
content, please consider becoming a
patron or a member here on YouTube. And
I'll be seeing you next time.
[music]